Marcel Lefebvre

Full Stack Web Developper at Freelance

marcel.lefebvre01@gmail.com

Summary

I'm a full stack web developper with experience in retail, wholesale and e-commerce sector. For some years I have worked as a salesman, managed an e-commerce website and a warehouse using web and server based tools; I believe it gives me a better understanding of what a client from these sectors might need. I am currently developing websites as a freelancer, building blogs and company sites from the ground up or using CMS applications like Wordpress; I also work on e-commerce platforms using open source software. I like learning new skills and trying to overcome new challenges. I love being taken out of my comfort zone. I enjoy working either alone or in a team, and I am a fan of open collaboration and using open source software. I particularly appreciate working with a mix of technical and non-technical people, as the variety of inputs and point of views generally lead to more interesting solutions. I have a college education in history, international studies and Japanese language, but I learned most of my programming skills online, through online classes and self-studying. I am currently freelancing while I pursue new opportunities and can be reached through this profile.

Experience

Full Stack Web Developper at Applika

April 2015 - Present (3 months)

Sales Representative at Canada Fighting Inc

October 2013 - March 2015 (1 year 6 months)

Prepare client orders, follow up to ensure customer satisfaction, communicate info and specials to important clients to boost sales.

Logistics Manager at Jukado Inc

August 2013 - February 2015 (1 year 7 months)

Oversee reception of inventory, plan organisation of the warehouse, optimize the order cycle to minimize shipping costs and manutention while maintaining inventory to an optimal level, oversee shipping and stocking in the warehouse

Sales Representative at Jukado Inc

May 2012 - August 2013 (1 year 4 months)

15 to 25 hours a week. Counseling and selling equipment to wholesale clients and working with the manager to organize the showroom. Helping in other areas such as delivery, shipping, merchandise reception, warehouse cleaning and organisation.

Certifications

Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree

Udacity April 2015

Languages

English(Native or bilingual proficiency)French(Native or bilingual proficiency)Japanese(Limited working proficiency)Spanish(Limited working proficiency)

Education

Université de Montréal - Ecole polytechnique de Montréal

Bachelor of Engineering (B.E.), Computer Science, 2012 - 2013

Université de Montréal

Master's degree, International/Global Studies, 2010 - 2012

Université de Montréal

Bachelor's degree, East Asian Studies, 2007 - 2010

Activities and Societies: Student representative for Japanese Studies, Japanese french language exchange

Udacity

Interests

Traditional Asian martial arts, combat sports, product design and branding, web and mobile app design, emerging technologies in education

Skills & Expertise

Web Development

Python

PHP

JavaScript

jQuery

HTML5

CSS

Bootstrap

WordPress

SOL

Agile Web Development

Procedure Development

Git

Github

Sales

Customer Service

Marcel Lefebvre

Full Stack Web Developper at Freelance

marcel.lefebvre01@gmail.com



Contact Marcel on LinkedIn